and they're really really smart.
And then often times they'll say, "Oh,
you know, I've had such a great
experience here. I'd like to stay in the
United States." Yeah, I bet you would. I
bet you would. So you can spy for China.
>> Do you think that's happening?
>> Every single day.
>> You think that Chinese students are in
America spying on behalf of China?
>> Yes.
>> How could you be so sure?
>> I'm 1,000% sure. How could you be so
sure?
>> Because we frequently arrest them and
then trade them for Americans who are in
Chinese prisons.
>> Yeah.
>> And they're masquerading as students.
>> Mhm. PhD candidates. Always in the hard
sciences. Always.
>> So, China are the long-term adversary.
And what is it that China China want?
What is it they're doing
>> and what is the outcome?
>> I think they want a couple of things. I
think that
on a more immediate basis they want
reunification with Taiwan. It's going to
happen someday. Even the Taiwanese will
tell you, "Yes, we're a part of China,
but we're kind of not a part of China.
We're not really independent, but we are
kind of independent." And even American
policy is that Taiwan is a part of
China, and eventually someday they'll be
reunited. Do you think with everything
that's going on at the moment with Trump
in Venezuela and Greenland, this is
going to create cover for
>> Oh, I was hoping you would ask me a
question like that. I think that's very
that's a very important issue that that
the media really aren't talking about.
So,
let's put it in the context of what
happened last week in Venezuela because
they're all moving parts of the same of
the same policy.
So,
we we sent a Delta Force squad into
Venezuela a week ago and we snatched
President Maduro and he faces
international narcotics trafficking
charges in New York. Okay, some people
are for that, some people are against
it. Whether you're for it or against it,
it's happened. There's nothing we can do
about it now. But
that operation may have inadvertently
given the green light to something that
both the Russians and the Chinese have
long sought. The United States really is
the only true superpower in the world.
You know, the Chinese have a lot more
people. They have lots of nuclear
missiles, but they have one aircraft
carrier. We have 12, soon to be 14. We
have way more long-distance bombers. We
have way more fighters. The Russians are
bogged down in a war in in Ukraine.
They're winning the war, but they're
bogged down nonetheless. So,
did this did this reinstitution of the
Monroe Doctrine saying that, you know,
from 1814 that that the Western
Hemisphere is the is the territory of
the United States, it's up to us to
protect it from foreign powers. Well, in
1814, that meant the British Navy. We
don't really need a Monroe Doctrine and
it's not up to us whether the Argentines
want to have good relations with China
for example.
We invoked the Monroe Doctrine in this
operation to snatch Maduro. So does that
mean then that if we have a sphere of
influence that is the Western Hemisphere
that the Chinese have a sphere of
influence that includes Taiwan that the
Russians have a sphere of influence that
includes Ukraine? because that's kind of
what it seems. It looks like we've given
the green light to both of those
countries and that we're conceding the
fact that it's a unipolar world right
now in favor of a multipolar world. Now,
personally, I think a multipolar world
is safer.
>> What's a multipolar world?
>> Multip-polar world is where there's not
just one superpower. There are three or
more.
So in terms of policy, this simple act
of just sending a team in to grab Maduro
has turned international diplomacy on
its head.
What do we do if the Chinese invade
Taiwan? Do we really want to send
American soldiers to, you know, to fight
and die for Taiwan?
>> What do you think would happen if China
tomorrow said, "You know what? We're
going to take Taiwan."
>> You know what? Honest to God, I think
nothing would happen.
I think we would rush to protect
Australia, Japan, South Korea, the
Philippines, Thailand. We'd rush to
protect them.
>> Why?
>> Because they're they're major non-NATO
allies. They're good friends, close
friends. But in terms of going to Taiwan
to fight Chinese soldiers,
I can't imagine it.
>> Trump told the New York Times that
whether China moves on Taiwan is
ultimately up to Chinese President Xi
Jong-ing. not the USA
he would be very unhappy if China
changed the status quo he claimed he
doesn't think will act while he's
president
>> see and that is actually what the
long-term policy is the long-term policy
is sure someday
to be determined later you guys can
unify
>> just don't do it while I'm here
>> yeah don't do it today
>> maybe when Trump goes
>> god forbid
So going back to this point, you said
they want Taiwan. What else do you think
China want?
>> Well,
do they want to see the US fall?
>> Yes, sure.
>> And are they actively doing things to
encourage that?
>> Yes, but not the things that
that you would expect.
Instead of running around the world, you
know, overthrowing governments, invading
countries, which is what we do,
they go to countries and say, "Hey, you
need a new highway system, we'll pay for
it. You need a new airport, no problem.
You need a new hospital, electrical
grid, we have plenty of money from our
gigantic trade surplus. We'll pay for
it. We just want to have really good,
friendly relations with you." And that's
what they do. The Chinese essentially
own Africa right now.
>> What are you most concerned about in the
world at the moment? What what does
actually keep you up at night?
>> What frightens me the most is that the
US government
over the last
well really over the last
50 years or 55 years has so inflated its
military budget
that what we spend on the Pentagon is
now more than the next eight largest
countries combined.
Right?
Donald Trump right now spends a a
trillion dollars a year on the Pentagon
budget. He's asking for next year to be
a trillion and a half.
We can't afford it. Our interest on the
national debt is now the third largest
expenditure in government between the
Pentagon and social security and then
the the interest on the debt.
>> And why does this bother you?
>> Because we're going bankrupt and all the
while the China the Chinese are letting
us spend ourselves into oblivion. The
Chinese don't spend that kind of money.
How come I can't have a bullet train
that goes 400 miles an hour? How come I
can't get to Chicago in 3 hours by
train? You know, how come the airports
in my country look like [__] and you go
to Chinese airports and they're pristine
with like the most amazing services and
the best restaurants? How come Chinese
roads don't have potholes? And in my
town, it's like driving across Bosnia.
It's because they decided not to spend
their money on weapons. They spend it on
infrastructure. Do you think that's
likely that the US could go bankrupt
effectively?
>> I do.
>> Yeah, I do. We can't keep up this pace.
It's not possible. We're going to have
to We're going to have to raise taxes
and cut the budget.
>> What's the most important thing that we
didn't talk about that we should have
talked about, John?
>> Oh, that's a good question.
One of the most important things in my
life, to tell you the truth, uh, is the
issue of ethics.
I love this country more than anything
else in the world and I want it to do
the right thing. We're a country of laws
and we have to obey our laws which is
why I blew the whistle on the torture
program.
>> Who's not obeying the laws?
>> Our government.
>> In what way?
>> We've gotten to the point and it started
around the year 2000 or 2001. We got to
the point where if we want to do
something, we just do it.
>> Like what?
>> In 1946,
we passed something called the Federal
Torture Act, which banned torture.
Okay. Also in 1946, we executed
Japanese soldiers who waterboarded
American prisoners of war. That was a
death penalty offense to waterboard
someone. All right. In 1968, on January
the 11th, 1968,
the Washington Post ran a front page
photograph of an American soldier
waterboarding a North Vietnamese
prisoner. When the when the picture ran,
the Secretary of Defense, Robert
McNamera, ordered an immediate
investigation. That soldier was
arrested. He was charged with torture
and he was sentenced to 20 years of hard
labor at Levvenworth.
And then in 2002,
it's legal. We can do it. We can do it
because we're the good guys.
The law never changed. We changed. And
my point was always either we're going
to be the good guys or we're not. Either
we're going to be what Ronald Reagan
called a shining city on a hill or we're
not. It when I was when I was stationed
in Bahrain, I was the human rights
officer. So, I had to write the human
rights report every year that we sent to
Congress. Well, imagine
if John goes in to see the Minister of
Interior, and I say, "Your Highness, you
cannot pick up a 15-year-old kid for
marching in a peaceful pro-democracy
demonstration and then murder him, beat
him to death in the in the police
station, and call his parents to come
and pick up the body. You can't do that.
I have to report that to Congress and
you're going to lose your your rights to
buy American military hardware. But then
the CIA station chief goes in an hour
later and says, "Don't pay any attention
to the human rights guy. I'll give you
$10 million. If you set up a secret
prison here, we're going to send you
some prisoners. You torture them and
then you give us a write up of
everything they say during torture."
Who's he going to listen to? Is he going
to listen to me?
>> Did that happen? Yes.
He's not going to listen to me.
If all of a sudden torture is legal just
cuz we say it is and then Congress is
like, "Oh, we don't know anything
because it's a secret program, so we
can't talk about it."
>> Do we still torture people?
>> No.
I am very proud to say that
when the McCain Feinstein anti-torrture
amendment was passed into law in
December of 2014, John McCain got up on
the floor of the Senate and said it was
because of me, because of my
revelations. He said, "If I had not told
the American people that the CIA was
torturing prisoners in their name, we
would never have known."
That's why I say it was worth it.
>> Do you think you should be pardoned by
by President Trump?
>> I do.
>> Have you written him?
>> I
I've
I have to be careful with my language
here. I applied. My name is in the
system. I have very
very high level supporters
who have approached him personally
and I'm hopeful that it happens.
John, we have a closing tradition where
the last guest leaves a question for the
next not knowing who they're going to be
leaving it for. And the question left
for you is, what's something you stopped
doing that improved your life more than
anything you started?
feeling sorry for myself.
I I'll be honest with you. I have
struggled with depression my entire
life.
And after my second divorce,
I went through this period where I was
just I couldn't pull myself out of bed
in the morning because I felt so sorry
for myself. Because of the divorce or
because of your life or because
>> the whole thing I I believed I was just
a loser. I was in my 50s,
unemployable,
convicted felon, barely able to make
ends meet, worried about where my rent
was coming from one month to the next.
And then I thought, "Fuck you. What's
wrong with you?
You don't have to answer to anybody."
And I I told myself, "No more feeling
sorry for myself. I was going to go make
a career on my own. And so I knew I
would never work for government again. I
knew I would never work in corporate
America again. After I left the CIA, I
was the head of the competitive
intelligence practice at Deote and
Touch, spying on Ernstston Young and PWC
and IBM, and it was great fun. I'll
never work in in the corporate world
again. So I decided I'm going to do what
I'm good at.
and I'm a I'm a terrific writer and I'm
told that I'm a gifted storyteller. So,
I'm going to write books. I have two
syndicated newspaper columns that run in
212 small town papers around the
country. I'm on TV all the time. I have
three podcasts, Drogram, every day on on
both YouTube and Rumble. Thanks for
letting me plug them, by the way.
>> Go ahead. uh Deep Focus on YouTube and
on Apple Podcast, John Kuryaku's Dead
Drop, which is just story after story
after story. And now I make a perfectly
great living. I I'm in a long-term
relationship with the woman I'm crazy
about, and life is good.
>> And it all started with that decision to
stop feeling sorry for yourself.
>> Yes. If people around me keep saying,
"You've done nothing wrong. You're a
hero for what you did." And deep down I
would do it again. Then why am I feeling
sorry for myself? I'm right. They're
wrong. They're criminals. So I'm just
going to go on with my life. And that
snapped me out of it.
So don't feel sorry for yourself.
Do something about it.
Act.
>> John, you are someone that is very good
at storytelling. You are. You've written
many books. I'm going to link all the
books below. Oh, thank you.
>> So many incredible books. I've got some
of them here with me on the floor. Um,
>> I could go through all them, but we need
another couple of days.
>> Um, John, thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you so much for your incredible
storytelling, your wisdom, but also just
giving us a window into a world that
most of us know nothing about because
there's so many lessons that I think are
pertinent to all of our lives riddled
amongst there. And I think, you know,
I hope you do get pardoned.
>> Thank you. I hope so. I've got my
fingers crossed. And when you do,
hopefully we can come back again and
have another conversation.
>> I look forward to that.
>> It's been such a pleasure.
>> Pleasure is mine. Thanks for the
invitation.
>> This is something that I've made for
you. I realize that the DVO audience are
strivvers. Whether it's in business or
health, we all have big goals that we
want to accomplish. And one of the
things I've learned is that when you aim
at the big big big goal, it can feel
incredibly psychologically uncomfortable
because it's kind of like being stood at
the foot of Mount Everest and looking
upwards. The way to accomplish your
goals is by breaking them down into tiny
small steps. And we call this in our
team the 1%. And actually this
philosophy is highly responsible for
much of our success here. So, what we've
done so that you at home can accomplish
any big goal that you have is we've made
these 1% diaries and we released these
last year and they all sold out. So, I
asked my team over and over again to
bring the diaries back, but also to
introduce some new colors and to make
some minor tweaks to the diary. So, now
we have a better range for you. So, if
you have a big goal in mind and you need
a framework and a process and some
motivation, then I highly recommend you
get one of these diaries before they all
sell out once again. And you can get
yours now at the diary.com where you can
get 20% off our Black Friday bundle. And
if you want the link, the link is in the
description.